All right, you're done. Let's look at the solution.
As I said in the question, we're going to be
working inside a forecast fragment in the update weather function.
First, we're going to need to create a standard intent
for our alarm receiver. We then add our location query
as an extra. We then wrap that in a pending
intent. A pending intent is a special kind of object
that describes an intent. This allows other applications to implement
the feature of the original intent that's used to
create the pending intent. We're only going to use this
pending intent once, so I set flag one shot.
Then, we get the alarm service and set the alarm
to trigger five seconds from now. But we still
need for our alarm to do something. Back in the
Broadcast Receiver, we need to send the standard intent
to start our service, and that's it. Let's try running
the app. All right, so now we've got the
Alarm Manager getting in the way of our service. We
hit refresh. It'll take us about five more seconds
before we actually see the data now. And there we
have it. A very, very simple alarm. Even with
this updating in the background potentially, and using a service,
we could still be more efficient in our use
of phone resources. Rato can tell us more about that.